Hello.
In this next lecture, we're going to make it so that we can damage our boss.
If we open up our boss blueprint and create a new variable and call this health.
Change this barrel type to be a float and go compile.
And for now, let's make it so our boss has ten house.
Then in some free space, right click and look for the event.
Any damage, node event, any damage.
We're going to get our health and subtract it from the amount of damage that we took.
Then we'll tell the game, This is our new health, so I'll drag in the health.
And look what set health and connect all these nodes.
After we do this, we want to create a new variable.
I just call this enemy damaged.
Change this rebel type to be a boolean.
And just drag it in and set it and make sure that we check this box.
We're not enemy damaged.
We're going to make it so it can't attack our player character.
So if we go over to the set time of event before we go to our jump mode, we're going to have a branch.
And the condition of that branch is going to be whether my enemy is damaged.
If my enemy is being damaged, we're going to make it so it can't attack our player character.
So bring the true link here and connect false into here.
Only if our enemy is not damaged, we'll allow it to attack our player character after we tell the game
that my enemy is damaged.
We're going to launch our enemy back in the direction that was hit.
So if we just close this and go over to our mushroom blueprint.
We can copy all the notes here.
Which are relating to where we launch our mushroom back when our player character hits them.
Oh, Kobe this and just paste this here.
And connect from get actor location to damage closer.
And then connect this into here.
So this will launch our boss back in the direction of wherever our player character hits them from.
And after we do this, we are going to drag in our bosses health.
And if this value is less than.
Well, equal to zero, then we are going to kill our boss.
However, if his value is more than zero, then we're just going to tell the game that our boss has
been damaged and we'll make it play.
It's damaged Flipbook.
So if I close this and go over to my boss animation blueprint.
Further to the new state machine and just right click and go jump and call this damaged.
Then if we just shrug off here and go animation state, select this and just rename this our boss damaged.
And if we head inside here and play the boss damaged animation.
And just connect this into here.
Whoops.
Then we go from boss damage to our idol when our boss damaged, animation has finished playing.
We'll enter our idol animation.
So I head inside here.
Right click and go.
Time remaining.
When the time remaining of this animation is less than 0.1 seconds, we'll transition back into our
idle animation.
If I compile this, I go back to my boss blueprint of a false.
If we just drag in our animation component from here.
If we get the animation instance.
And call the jump to know.
And for the name I called mine damaged.
So I'm going to type this in here.
I think folks into here.
Then if we just drag up here and look for trigger will delay.
And for the time put one after a trivial delay of one second will tell the game that our boss is no
longer damaged.
So the way a retractable delay will work is if, say, my player character attacks my boss twice, then
this ritual will delay, will not complete unless it's just allowed to complete without being called
again.
Okay.
So we can just compile and test everything out.
If I get compile, if I go play and I attack my boss, they'll be launched back and then they'll play
that boss damage animation.
Although you may have noticed, after I damage my boss, it's moving a lot more slowly.
And that is because when we launch our character, we change them to enter their fooling mode.
If you remember at the start, I made it so my boss is in flying mode, so its default land movement
mode is flying.
However, when we call the launch character mode, this forces our boss to enter the following state
to get a better picture of what I mean on a stick.
I am just going to drag in my character movement, drag up here and not forget movement mode.
And I'm just going to right click and look for print shrink and connect bits into here.
So if I go to compile and play, my boss is in flying movement mode.
However, when I hit them, they enter polling movement mode, which is why they're moving so slowly.
So in order to fix this, after we launch our bus, we're going to drive up here and look for sequence.
And first, we're just going to do what we normally do.
Then after a delay.
Of around 0.7 seconds.
We're going to drag in our character movement and drag up here and look for set movement mode.
And set it to be flying.
And just connect this into here.
Also, when I launch my bus back, they move really far back.
So if we set character movement and look for friction.
Under falling lateral friction per value or something like.
To that way our boss won't be launched too far back.
And now if I go compile and play.
But I hate my boss that we launched back a bit.
And then after 0.8 seconds that entered flying mode again.
I'm actually just going to decrease the lateral friction of it, so I may get 1.7.
That way they're not a bit further back.
Okay.
And with this, we can damage our boss.
The next thing we're going to do is make it to our boss.
Can die.